TERRY G LORBER

www.rideside.net/ \sim tgl \diamond tgl@rideside.net \diamond +1-781-632-0733

PROFILE

Consensus-building leader of cross-functional product development teams. I've developed strategy and implemented product roadmaps for startups to \$100mil global businesses. Pro-active project manager experienced with quality systems for medical devices (21 CFR 820, IEC 62304, ISO 14971).

EXPERIENCE

Alloy Enterprises

June 2022 - November 2024

Burlington, MA

Software Engineer, Architect

- · Planned, built, and maintained proprietary CAD/CAM software to support Alloy's novel manufacturing process. Collaborated across disciplines to unlock aluminum components at scale.
- · Software Engineering, Computational Geometry, Manufacturing, Python, C++

Metatooth

December 2018 - present

Owner

Swampscott, MA

· Consulting services in advanced manufacturing, technology integration, and product development.

LightForce Orthodontics

VP of Software

August 2017 - December 2018

Cambridge, MA

- · Joined this pre-seed round dental startup as first software hire. Responsible for medical device and workflow software in support of company's first sale. Deployed cloud-native software stack for LightForce's first 510(K). Contributed system architecture, implementation, regulatory documentation, project management, and product management.
- · Medical Devices, FDA, JavaScript, C++, Computational Geometry
- 510(K) No. K183542 Signature Orthodontics System, 2019-01-02
- 510(K) No. K181271 Signature Orthodontics System, 2018-06-13

Atlantis - Dentsply Sirona

August 2010 - August 2017

Director, Global Digital Product Development

Waltham, MA

- · Responsible for digital dentistry strategy and project planning for \$100mil global business. Leader of cross-functional product development team that launched Atlantis' first digital product. Collaborated with business partners to deliver integrated digital workflows.
- · Product Development, Cross-functional Team Leadership, Medical Devices, Manufacturing, Business Development
- · US Patent No. 10,390,910 B2 INTEGRATED DENTAL IMPLANT COMPONENT AND TOOL FOR PLACEMENT OF A DENTAL IMPLANT COMPONENT
- · US Patent No. D787,061S SCAN BODY FOR DENTAL IMPLANT PROCEDURES

Atlantis - Astra Tech

January 2007 - July 2010

Consulting Software Engineer

Waltham, MA

- · Technical owner of industry leading B2B platform. Full stack development using JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, and C++. Collaborated with business partners to deliver integrated digital dentistry workflows.
- · Software Engineering, Medical Devices, Manufacturing, Ruby on Rails, C++, Computational Geometry

Atlantis Components

Senior Software Engineer

August 2000 - January 2007 Cambridge, MA

- · First software hire for this dental startup. Supported sales & manufacture of industry's first CAD/CAM dental implant abutment. Automation of data acquisition, product design, and manufacturing workflows
- · Software Engineering, Medical Devices, Manufacturing, C++, Ruby on Rails

Freudenberg Sealing Technologies

June 1996 - September 1999

Bristol, NH

· Product design, prototyping, and testing in support of sales and manufacturing. My first experience with Kaizen and continuous improvement culture.

· C, Siemens NX, Computer-Aided Design (CAD), Manufacturing

EDUCATION

Product Engineer

Boston University, Boston, MA

September 2013

M.S. in Computer Science

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI

May 1996

B.S. in Engineering (Mechanical Engineering)

SKILLS

Computer Languages	Bash, C++, JavaScript, Python, R, Ruby, SQL, TypeScript
Operating Systems	Browsers (Chrome, Firefox), Linux (Ubuntu), macOS, Windows
Protocols & APIs	HTTPS, JSON, REST, RPC, WSS, XML, YAML
Databases	MS SQL Server, PostgreSQL, Redis, Sqlite3
Web & App servers	flask, NGINX, node.js, puma
Tools	AWS, Azure, CMake, Docker, Emacs, GitHub, Jira, WordPress
Frameworks	CGAL, FLTK, Node.js, OpenGL, OpenMesh, Ruby on Rails,
	Sinatra.rb, three.js, Unidraw, VTK, Vue.js
Methodologies	Agile, Continuous Improvement, Kaizen, KanBan
Infleuncers	Atwood's Coding Horror, Beck's XP, Booch's UML,
	Brooks' The Mythical Man-Month, DeMarco & Lister's Peopleware,
	Fowler's Continuous Integration, Spolsky's Joel on Software,
	Gamma, Helm, Johnson, and Vlissides's Design Patterns,
	Tufte's Visual Display of Quantitative Information

EXTRA

Programmer, Gardener, Brewer, Hiker, Surfer, Telemark skier

Town Meeting Member — Swampscott, MA — 2018-2024

Cubmaster Pack 55 — Swampscott, MA — 2018-2021

UM College of Engineering Leadership Honor Society — Ann Arbor, MI — 1995-1996

Eagle Scout Troop 295 — Concord, NH — 1991